- 让我们来看看基于子词的分词。
- Let's take a look at subword based tokenization.
了解为什么基于子词的分词是
Understanding why subword based tokenization is
有趣需要理解缺陷
interesting requires understanding the flaws
基于单词和基于校正器的标记化。
of word based and corrector based tokenization.
如果你还没有看过第一个视频
If you haven't seen the first videos
基于单词和基于字符的标记化
on word based and character based tokenization
我们建议你检查它们
we recommend you check them
在看这个视频之前。
out before looking at this video.
基于子词的标记化介于基于字符之间
Subword based tokenization lies in between character based
和基于词的分词算法。
and word based tokenization algorithms.
这个想法是找到一个中间立场
The idea is to find a middle ground
在非常大的词汇表之间
between very large vocabularies
大量的词汇标记
a large quantity of out vocabulary tokens
并且在非常相似的词中失去意义
and a loss of meaning across very similar words
用于基于词的分词器和非常长的序列
for word based tokenizers and very long sequences
以及意义不大的单个标记。
as well as less meaningful individual tokens.
对于基于字符的分词器。
For character based tokenizers.
这些算法依赖于以下原则。
These algorithms rely on the following principle.
常用词不宜拆分
Frequently used words should not be split
分成更小的子词
into smaller subwords
而稀有词应该被分解
while rare words should be decomposed
成有意义的子词。
into meaningful subwords.
一个例子是狗这个词。
An example is the word dog.
我们想让我们的分词器有一个单一的 ID
We would like to have our tokenizer to have a single ID
对于狗这个词
for the word dog rather
而不是将其拆分为校正器 DO 和 G。
than splitting it into correctors D O and G.
然而，当遇到狗这个词时
However, when encountering the word dogs
我们希望我们的标记化从根本上理解这一点
we would like our tokenize to understand that at the root
这还是狗这个词。
this is still the word dog.
添加 S 后，意思略有改变
With an added S, that slightly changes the meaning
同时保持最初的想法。
while keeping the original idea.
另一个例子是像标记化这样的复杂词
Another example is a complex word like tokenization
可以拆分成有意义的子词。
which can be split into meaningful subwords.
根
The root
这个词的是记号，-ization 完成根
of the word is token and -ization completes the root
赋予它稍微不同的含义。
to give it a slightly different meaning.
拆分这个词是有道理的
It makes sense to split the word
一分为二，token 作为词根，
into two, token as the root of the word,
标记为单词的开头
labeled as the start of the word
和化作为标记的附加信息
and ization as additional information labeled
作为单词的完成。
as a completion of the word.
反过来，该模型现在将能够有意义
In turn, the model will now be able to make sense
不同情况下的令牌。
of token in different situations.
它会理解这个词的 token, tokens, tokenizing
It will understand that the word's token, tokens, tokenizing
和标记化具有相似的含义并且是相关联的。
and tokenization have a similar meaning and are linked.
它还将理解标记化、现代化
It's will also understand that tokenization, modernization
和免疫，它们都有相同的后缀
and immunization, which all have the same suffixes
可能在相同的句法情况下使用。
are probably used in the same syntactic situations.
基于子词的分词器通常有办法
Subword based tokenizers generally have a way to
识别哪些标记是单词的开头
identify which tokens are a start of word
以及哪些标记完成单词的开头。
and which tokens complete start of words.
所以这里以令牌为开始
So here token as the start
病房和哈希哈希化作为奖励的完成。
of a ward and hash hash ization as completion of award.
这里 hash 哈希前缀表示化是一部分
Here, the hash hash prefix indicates that ization is part
奖项而不是它的开始。
of award rather than the beginning of it.
hash 散列来了
The hash hash comes
来自基于词片算法的 BERT 分词器。
from the BERT tokenizer based on the word piece algorithm.
其他标记化使用其他前缀可以是
Other tokenizes use other prefixes which can be
放置以表示单词的一部分
placed to indicate part of words
喜欢在这里或单词的开头。
like in here or start of words instead.
有很多
There are a lot
可以使用的不同算法
of different algorithms that can be used
用于子词标记化
for subword tokenization
大多数模型都获得了最先进的结果
and most models obtaining state-of-the-art results
今日英语
in English today
使用某种子词标记化算法。
use some kind of subword tokenization algorithms.
这些方法有助于减少词汇量
These approaches help in reducing the vocabulary sizes
通过跨不同的词共享信息
by sharing information across different words
有前缀的能力
having the ability to have prefixes
和后缀这样理解。
and suffixes understood as such.
他们在非常相似的词中保留意义
They keep meaning across very similar words
通过识别相似的标记，将它们组合起来。
by recognizing similar tokens, making them up.